Records of the School of Advanced International Studies, Asian Studies 1968-1982 07.110
The Ferdinand Hamburger Archives, The Milton S. Eisenhower Library, The Johns Hopkins University
Records of the School of Advanced International Studies, Asian Studies 1968-1982
Record Group Number 07.110
Department of Asian Studies, School of Advanced International Studies, The Johns Hopkins University
The Ferdinand Hamburger Archives, The Milton S. Eisenhower Library, The Johns Hopkins University
0.5 cubic foot (1.5 document cases)
The records of the Asian Studies curriculum are very limited in scope. They are contained in two series: (1) Correspondence, 1974-1982, and (2) Student Records, 1968-1977. Although they range in date from 1968 to 1982, the bulk of the records, the chronological correspondence of Nathaniel Thayer, spans only the period 1977 to 1982. The records highlight the duties and interests of a faculty member in the field of Asian Studies. In the correspondence, Thayer discusses his travel, research, professional colleagues, international political figures, current international situations and his professional work in Asia.
Administrative Information
Provenance
These records were transferred to the Archives by Veronica Barker, the Administrative Assistant for Economics and Asian Studies.
History
Asian Studies has been a part of the SAIS curriculum since SAIS was incorporated into the Johns Hopkins University in 1950. The original faculty position in this field was Professor of Asiatic Politics and was augmented by and eventually replaced by the position of Professor of Asian Studies. Like all other departments at SAIS, Asian Studies is able to offer a wide variety of courses on China, Japan and Southeast Asia through the use of Professorial Lecturers. The course offerings reflect an emphasis on politics, international relations and international economics.
Description of Series/Container List
  Correspondence
- Correspondence, 1974-1982
  Series 1, correspondence, is the chronological correspondence files of Nathaniel Thayer, the Director of Asian Studies. Dating from 1974 to 1982, the records consist almost entirely of outgoing carbon copies, with few incoming letters, and include correspondence with colleagues, both in the U.S. and abroad and correspondence regarding teaching and curriculum. The records are filed chronologically and within files in reverse chronological order.
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence, January-June, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence, July-December, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Confidential) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence, January-May, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence, June-December, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1977 (Confidential) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence, January-December, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence, January-December, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Confidential) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Chronological Correspondence, January-June, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Chronological Correspondence, July-December, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1980 (Confidential) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Chronological Correspondence, January-June, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Chronological Correspondence, July 1981 - June 1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Chronological Correspondence, September-December, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Confidential) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Student Records
- Student Records, 1968-1977
  Series 2, student records, consists of files on Ph.D. candidates from 1968 to 1977. They are few in number and are often records of students who began studying at SAIS before Thayer's tenure began. The records are made up of correspondence and student work, such as dissertation proposals and research papers. The series is filed in alphabetical order by last name of the individual and, within files, in reverse chronological order.
  - Ph.D. Candidates: Robert Bruce, 1970-1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ph.D. Candidates: Kylin Chhor, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ph.D. Candidates: Matthew Gardner, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ph.D. Candidates: Kent Harrington, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ph.D. Candidates: Odell Lee, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ph.D. Candidates: Charles Morrison, 1968-1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ph.D. Candidates: Ronald Myers, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ph.D. Candidates: John Katsuro Sakoh, c. 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ph.D. Candidates: Edward Windsor, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)